AHSANSHAHID

SENIOR FULL STACK DEVELOPER



ahsandev.work@gmail.com



https://ahsan-sha.github.io/Portfolio/



6622780776



181 Gilla Dr Ballwin, MO



SUMMARY

Ahsan is a Senior Full Stack Web Developer with well over 10 years of professional experience in developing web applications and beautiful websites from scratch. He has a Bachelor of Computer Science from University of Arkansas. His journey as a web developer has been impressive and he continues to grow and learn every day. Ahsan is a great fit for any start up or web agency, with his range of skills he has the ability to take on any size project or client and deliver a product or website that meets today's web standards and expectations.



EDUCATION

University of Arkansas

BS in Computer Sciences September 2011 – April 2013



CERTIFICATION

- · Zend Certified PHP Engineer
- Microsoft Certified Specialist with HTML5, CSS3 and JavaScript
- Adobe Certified Expert

PROFILE

Proficient and creative WordPress developer with 5+ years of experience in website management and development. Experienced in SEO and PPC campaign creation. Expert in all aspects of WordPress website creation, including design, plug-ins, and implementation. Skilled in creating engaging and interactive websites. Excel at team projects and leadership. Detail-oriented and knowledgeable in various programming languages.

CORE COMPETENCIES

WordPress · Beck-End & Front-End Development · Web Application Development · Software Engineering Computer Information Systems · Single-Webpage Application · Database Development

Advanced Coding · Troubleshooting & Debugging · Testing & Analysis · Solution Design · Leadership

Communication · Adaptability · Teamwork · Problem Solving · Goal-Oriented

SKILLS

PROGRAMMING

- Knowledge of OOP / Design Patterns
- Expert in PHP, Proficient in MVC
- Web Services, API, JSON, XML

DATABASES

- Relational Databases
 MySQL, SQL
- NoSQL Databases
 MongoDB

WEB RELATED

- WordPress, Shopify, React, jQuery
- Larave, VueJS, HTML5, CSS3, AJAX
- Bootstrap, AnimateJS, BounceJS.
- Theme Customization, Plugin Development
- Page Builder Plugins, Woocommerce

METHODOLOGIES:

Agile, Scrum

FRAMEWORKS

- Laravel, VueJS, Codelgniter, Symphony,
- CMS / Ecommerce Systems (WordPress,
- OpenCart, Shopify, Big-Commerce)

LANGUAGES

- PHP, JavaScript, HTML
- SASS, TailWilnd

SERVER SOFTWARE

- Linux (Ubuntu)
- LAMP, XAMPP, Apache
- SSH, cPanel, FTP

SOFTWARES

- Git (Github, GitLab, BitBucket)
- PhpStorm, Visual Studio Code, Sublime
- Photoshop, XD, Illustrator, Sketch, InDesign

WORK EXPERIENCE

APOGEE INVENT

FULL STACK PHP DEVELOPER

Mar 2019 - Apr 2022

It's a client-based product showcasing service. Develop functional and fast -responsive web applications. Developing and designing Restful services and APIs. Integration of code, Unit Testing and Deployment of Developed applications. Write comprehensive manuals, guides, and documents. Collaborate with developers, designers, sysadmins, and customers.

- The backend is in vanilla PHP and for the frontend different platforms like WordPress, Angular JS
 VUE JS and Shopify.
- Reviewed code, debugged problems and corrected issues.
- I developed the e-commerce module with different payment gateways with additional day to day

tasks and client specific sites. So the idea is to have a product with minimal features which then on client's request, custom modules would be added in as per the requirements.

- Consulted with engineering team members to determine system loads and develop improvement plans.
- Delivered performance-driven and user-centric websites that met all business requirements.
- Developed custom WordPress plugins And Developed API's using PHP, JavaScript and CSS.
- Manage back-end services and interchange of data between server and user, including server-side logic and database integration.
- Coordinated weekly team meeting with all WordPress engineers. Maintain GIT repositories and Pantheon environments.
- Responsible for translating designs and concepts into highly usable and engaging web
 applications using a variety of technologies

FORKLIFT TRAINING

Feb 2018 - Feb 2019

WORDPRESS DEVELOPER

- Designed complex WordPress solutions for back- end and front-end development to establish and guide website architecture and functionality
- Develop functional and fast-responsive web applications.
- Worked on React.JS components, Forms, Events, Keys, Router, Animations and Flux concept.
- Enhanced user experience by designing new web features using MVC Framework like Angular
- Used PHP as a proxy to interact with Rest services and interacting with Database.
- Created a responsive theme as per the design provided.
- Constructed a personalised interface based on user preferences and activity.
- Created custom multistep forms with programmatic calculation, based on user login and field values
- Customised an already built plugin as per client requirements.
- Synced up two websites using WP-JSON and REST API.
- Optimised the website for Google Pagespeed and YSlow.
- Developed a new base WordPress theme for building new websites.
- Working with Elementor, Avada, Divi to develop website
- Customised themes to meet clients' requirements.

BIG DROP INC

Jan 2017 - Jan 2018

WORDPRESS / PHP DEVELOPER

- Developed Custom HTML/CSS and custom JavaScript for Web Applications.
- Customized WordPress plugins and built new custom plugins.
- Responsible for installing, configuring and maintaining, PHP, Apache, and MySQL on AWS cloud servers.
 Developed a new base WordPress theme for building new websites.
- Involved in writing application level code to interact with APIs, Web Services using AJAX, JSON and XML.
- Use Team Collaboration Software JIRA and Confluence.
- $\bullet \hspace{0.4cm}$ Optimized the translation process for a large multilingual site
- Collaborated extensively with the marketing and SEO teams.
- Deploy Developed website into hosting and optimize performance on server SEO of website using plugins.
- Developed, tested, and maintained current systems written in PHP
- Built a custom learning management system from the ground up using ACF and Gravity Forms.
- Manage a user guide to help clients understand site features and management of website to increase visitor satisfaction
- Spearheaded content management system (CMS) process improvements to maintain high performance and availability
 of technical components to support clients
- Introduced new plug-ins and extensions to make the website more usable and interactive.
- Solid knowledge on SOAP and Restful web services
- Extensively used the Angular js frame works, JSON and JavaScript frameworks jQuery